A Guide to the Dept. of General Services, Architectural drawings, plans, and specifications, ca. 1919-2002
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Dept. of General Services, Architectural drawings, plans, and specifications, ca. 1919-2002
The Library of Virginia
42516
154 sheets; Blueprints, Diazo prints, ink on paper, microfiche, and electrostatic prints.
Virginia. Dept. of General Services
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to architectural and engineering plans and drawings of current governmental buildings requires a written request from the prospective user and written authorization from the appropriate authority within the agency occupying the facility.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Dept. of General Services, Bureau of Facilities Managment, 1 March 2006.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of architectural drawings for various state buildings from the Plan Room of the Bureau of Facilities Management, Department of General Services. The drawings include elevations, floor plans, sections, details, renderings, proposed plans, and specifications for Broad Street Station, Capitol Building, Executive Mansion, Dove Street Armory, Motor Vehicles Building (12th & Main), Federal Reserve Bank, Virginia Holocaust Museum, Home for Needy Confederate Women (Virginia Museum of Fine Arts), Confederate Memorial Chapel (Virginia Museum of Fine Arts), Robinson House Garage (Virginia Museum of Fine Arts), Virginia State Penitentiary, Virginia Retirement System Building (Planters National Bank). Architects represented include Carneal Johnston and Wright(Richmond, Va.), Taylor and Fisher (Baltimore, Md.), Glave Newman Anderson and Associates (Richmond, Va.), Ballou and Justice (Richmond, Va.), Hanbury Evans Wright Vlattas + Co. (Norfolk, Va.), Joseph Dye Lahendro, Lee Smith and Van Dervoort (Richmond, Va.), and Alfred C. Bossom.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by agency/building and chronologically there under.
Contents List
- Broad Street Station (Science Museum of Virginia)
  - Master Plan- Broad Street Station 1985, print on foam board; 42.5 x 25 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/1, Folder 1)
    Architect: Glave Newman Anderson & Associates, Inc.
  - The Broad Street Station Complex, 1990-2010 ca.1990, 2 sheets; print on foam board; 19 x 25 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/1, Folder 1)
    Unsigned.
- Capitol Building
  - [Capitol Interior, Condition of Finishes], 2002, 10 sheets; photographs on foam core; 22 x 29 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/2, Folder 2)
    Architect: Hanbury Evans Wright Vlattas + Co.(HEWV) with WRT Study
- Dove Street Armory
  - Dove Street Armory 1963, 27 sheets; Diazo print; 45 x 32 in. (Box 1)
    Architect: Ballou and Justice, Architects-Engineers; As-Built Drawings
- Executive Mansion
  - Governor's Mansion, Showing Millstones, Richmond, Virginia, 1941, 1 sheet; Blueprint; 16 x 24 in. (Box 1)
    Signed by: H. J. Neale
  - Garden and Wall Enclosures for The Governor's Mansion, Richmond, Virginia 1954, 3 sheets; Blueprints and Diazo print; 27 x 49 in. and smaller. (Box 1)
    Architect: Ballou and Justice, Architects-Engineers
  - Suggested Landscape Treatment of Kitchen Entrance Area, The Governor's Mansion 1958, 1 sheet; Diazo print; 26 x 32 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 3)
    Signed: R. L. Nicar
  - Executive Mansion [lithograph] 1987, 1 sheet; Lithograph; 18 x 22 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 3)
    Signed: Vernon P. Johnson; No. 805/950
  - Lead Based Paint Surveys- Governor's Mansion and Cottage, Spectrum Analyzer XRF Readings 1994, 23 leaves (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Inspector: Scott Smith
  - Executive Mansion, First and Second Floor n.d., 2 sheets; Blueprints; 26.5 x 37 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 3)
    Unsigned
- Motor Vehicle Department (12th & Main Building)
  - Alterations to Building at Richmond, Va., for Motor Vehicle Dept., State of Virginia 1932, 8 sheets; Blueprints; 36 x 18 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 4)
    Architects: Carneal, Johnston & Wright, Architects and Engineers
  - Floor Plans Showing Proposed Arrangement of Offices, Division of Motor Vehicles, 12th and Main St. 1938, 4 sheets; Ink on linen; 23 x 17 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 4)
- Supreme Court of Appeals (Old Federal Reserve Building)
  - Proposed Alterations and Additions to The Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond ca. 1930, 29 sheets; Photostatic copies and pencil on paper; 16 x 12.5 in. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Architects: Taylor and Fisher, Architects, Baltimore, MD
  - Office Building for Federal Reserve Bank, Richmond, Virginia ca. 1930, 12 sheets; Pencil and colored pencil on paper; 20 x 25 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 5)
    Architects: Carneal, Johnston, and Wright, Architects-Engineers
  - Pew Type Seating, Supreme Court Room, Federal Reserve Building, Richmond, Virginia 1981, 8 sheets; Diazo prints; 39 x 30 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 6)
    Signed: New Holland Church Furniture, New Holland, Pa.
- Virginia Holocaust Museum
  - Adaptive Reuse of the Climax Warehouse for The Virginia Holocaust Museum 2001, 12 sheets; Electrostatic prints; 30 x 42.5 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 7)
    Architect: Joseph Dye Lahendro, Architect; Includes specifications.
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
  - Home for Needy Confederate Women, Richmond, Virginia 1930, Microfiche (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Architect: Lee, Smith & Van Dervoort, Architects and Engineers; Includes specifications.
  - Basement Plan, Confederate Chapel ca. 1960, 1 sheet (2 copies); Pencil on paper, Diazo print; 13 x 16 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 8)
  - Cupboard for Confederate Chapel ca. 1977, 2 sheets; Pencil on paper; 26 x 18.5 in and smaller. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 8)
  - New Front Steps for Confederate Chapel, Grove Avenue, Richmond, Virginia ca. 1977, 1 sheet; Pencil on paper; 14.5 x 36 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 8)
  - Alms Box, Confederate Chapel, Grove Avenue, Richmond, Virginia ca. 1977, 1 sheet; Pencil on paper; 24 x 36 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 8)
  - R. E. Lee Camp Memorial Chapel, 2900 Grove Ave., Richmond, Virginia ca. 1977, 1 sheet; Pencil on paper; 26 x 35 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 8)
    Signed: Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor's Office, Division of the Budget, Section of Engineering.
  - Additions and Alterations to Robinson House Garage, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Richmond, Virginia. 1981, 7 sheets; Diazo prints; 24 x 36 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 9)
    Architects: Stiles L. Hartley, Architect.
- Virginia Penitentiary
  - Hall and Shop Building, Virginia State Penitentiary, Richmond, Virginia 1927, 22 sheets; Diazo prints; 28 x 36 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 10)
    Architects: Carneal and Johnston, Architects-Engineers.
- Virginia Retirement System (Planters National Bank)
  - Alterations and Additions to Planters National Bank, Richmond, Virginia 1919, 6 sheets; Blueprints; 18 x 30 in. (Cabinet 4/G/9/3, Folder 11)
    Architects: Carneal and Johnston, Richmond, Virginia and Alfred C. Bossom, New York City, Associated Architects.